First of all, I'm a geek.
أولا .. أنا مهووسة
I'm an organic food-eating,
فأنا أأكل الطعام العضوي فقط
carbon footprint-minimizing, robotic surgery geek.
ومهووسة بكمية الكربون التي أصدرها .. ومهووسة بالجراحية بواسطة الرجال الآلية
And I really want to build green,
وأنا أريد حقاً أن أبني بيوت بيئية
but I'm very suspicious
ولكني أشك دوماً
of all of these well-meaning articles,
بكل تلك المقالات عن المعنى الحقيقي للحياة
people long on moral authority
فهنالك الكثير من الدوافع الاخلاقية ولكن
and short on data,
نقص كبير في المعلومات الجدية
telling me how to do these kinds of things.
التي تخبرني عن كيفية القيام بتلك الاشياء
And so I have to figure this out for myself.
لذا يتوجب عليّ معرفة ذلك بنفسي
For example: Is this evil?
على سبيل المثال : هل هذا سيء ؟
I have dropped a blob of organic yogurt
لقد وقعت مني قطرة من الزبادي العضوي
from happy self-actualized local cows
استخرجت من الأبقار المحلية السعيدة التي ترعى بنفسها
on my counter top,
على سطح المجلى خاصتي
and I grab a paper towel and I want to wipe it up.
فأحضرت منديل ورقي لكي أزيلها
But can I use a paper towel? (Laughter)
ولكن خطر ببالي .. هل يجب أن استخدم هذا المنديل ؟ ( ضحك)
The answer to this can be found in embodied energy.
والإجابة تكمن في الطاقة التي يمثلها ذلك المنديل - الطاقة المجسمة -
This is the amount of energy that goes into
وهي كمية الطاقة والماء التي تستخدم في
any paper towel or embodied water,
لصناعة أي منديل ورقي
and every time I use a paper towel,
وفي كل مرة أستخدم فيها المنديل الورقي
I am using this much
فأنا استخدم هذا القدر
virtual energy and water.
من الطاقة العملية ومن الماء
Wipe it up, throw it away.
أزيل قطرة الزبادي وأرمي المنديل
Now, if I compare that to a cotton towel
الآن إن قارنت هذا مع منديل قطني
that I can use a thousand times,
والذي يمكن أن أستخدمه الآف المرات
I don't have a whole lot of embodied energy
وهنا لا توجد طاقة مجسدة كبيرة فيها .
until I wash that yogurty towel.
حتى أقوم بغسله لإزالة الزبادي من عليه
This is now operating energy.
وهذه تسمى الطاقة التشغيلية
So if I throw my towel in the washing machine,
وإن وضعت هذا المنديل في الغسالة أوتوماتيكية
I've now put energy and water
سوف أعيد الطاقة والماء
back into that towel ...
إلى ذلك المنديل
unless I use a front-loading, high-efficiency washing machine, (Laughter)
إلا لو إستخدمت الغسالة أوتوماتيكية عالية الكفاءة والتي تعبأ من الامام
and then it looks a little bit better.
وهكذا سيبدو الامر أفضل
But what about a recycled paper towel
ولكن ماذا لو استخدمت منديل معاد تصنيعه
that comes in those little half sheets?
والذي يأتي بشكل نصف ورقة
Well, now a paper towel looks better.
والآن يبدو المنديل الورقي أفضل
Screw the paper towels. Let's go to a sponge.
دعونا نرمي المناديل جانباً .. لنستخدم إسفنجة
I wipe it up with a sponge, and I put it under the running water,
لقد أزلت القطرة بواسطة الإسفنجة .. ومن ثم وضعتها أسفل صنبور المياه الجاري
and I have a lot less energy and a lot more water.
وفي هذه الحالة .. فأنا لدي طاقة أقل ولكن ماء مهدور أكثر
Unless you're like me and you leave the handle
إلا لو كنتم مثلي حيث أترك الصنبور مفتوح ..
in the position of hot even when you turn it on,
على الوضعية الساخنة
and then you start to use more energy.
وهنا تبدأ باستخدام طاقة أكبر
Or worse, you let it run until it's warm
أو أسوء من هذا .. إن انتظرت أن تسخن المياه
to rinse out your towel.
لكي تشطف كامل الإسفنجة
And now all bets are off.
وهنا فأنت تربح كل الرهانات - بالهدر الأكبر -
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So what this says is that
ولكن ماذا يعني كل هذا
sometimes the things that you least expect --
يعني أن الاشياء التي لا تخطر على بالك
the position in which you put the handle --
أي ككيفية فتح الصنبور
have a bigger effect than any of those other things
لديها التاثير الاكبر من باقي كل الاشياء السابقة
that you were trying to optimize.
والتي تحاول انت ان تجعلها الافضل
Now imagine someone as twisted as me
والان تخيل شخص " مهووس " مثلي
trying to build a house.
يحاول أن يبني بيتاً
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That's what my husband and I are doing right now.
وهذا ما أقوم به أنا وزوجي الان
And so, we wanted to know, how green could we be?
ولقد أردنا أن نعلم كم من القدر يمكن ان نبني بيوت بيئية
And there's a thousand and one articles out there
وهنالك الآلاف من المقالات حولنا
telling us how to make all these green trade-offs.
والتي تخبرنا عن كيفية القيام بخيارات بيئية
And they are just as suspect
وجميعا كما توقعنا
in telling us to optimize these little things around the edges
تخبرنا كيفية تحسين تلك الامور الصغيرة حتى الحد الاقصى
and missing the elephant in the living room.
وتهمل القضية الكبرى الحقيقية التي تواجهنا
Now, the average house
الان لبناء بيت متوسط
has about 300 megawatt hours
فانه يحتاج ما يقارب 300 ميغا وات ساعية
of embodied energy in it;
من الطاقة المجسدة فيه
this is the energy it takes to make it --
وهذه هي الطاقة التي يحتاجها المنزل لانشاءه
millions and millions of paper towels.
هي تمثل الملاين والملاين من المناديل الورقية
We wanted to know how much better we could do.
ولقد أردنا أن نعلم - انا وزوجي - كيف يمكن أن نكون أفضل
And so, like many people,
لذا وكما باقي الاشخاص
we start with a house on a lot,
قمنا ببناء منزل على رقعة أرض
and I'm going to show you a typical construction on the top
وسوف أريكم منزل حقيقي في الظاهر
and what we're doing on the bottom.
وما نقوم به بالفعل في الباطن
So first, we demolish it.
بداية نحن ندمر المنزل القديم
It takes some energy, but if you deconstruct it --
وهذا يتطلب طاقة .. ولكن إن اعدت بناءه
you take it all apart, you use the bits --
أي بتفيكه بأكمله .. ومن ثم إستخدام ما يمكن إستخدامه
you can get some of that energy back.
فأن تكسب طاقة في هذه الحالة
We then dug a big hole
ومن ثم نحن نقوم بحفر حفرة كبيرة
to put in a rainwater catchment tank
لكي نضع خزانات تجميع مياه الامطار فيها
to take our yard water independent.
لكي نحصل على قطعة ارض مستقلة مائياً
And then we poured a big foundation
ومن ثم نصب أساسات كبيرة
for passive solar.
لاستخدام الطاقة الشمسية بصورة غير مباشرة للتدفئة
Now, you can reduce the embodied energy
ويمكننا تقليل الطاقة المجسدة في تلك العملية
by about 25 percent
بنسبة 25%
by using high fly ash concrete.
إن استخدمنا بيتون يحوي نسبة عالية من الرماد المتطاير
We then put in framing.
ومن ثم نضع الإطارات
And so this is framing -- lumber,
وهذه هي الاطارات وهي من الخشب
composite materials --
أو المواد المختلطة
and it's kind of hard to get the embodied energy out of that,
وهذه العملية يصعب تقليل الطاقة المجسدة فيها
but it can be a sustainable resource
ولكن يمكن استخدام مصادر مستدامة لتصنيعها
if you use FSC-certified lumber.
كما في حال استخدام خشب مؤسسة " إف . إس . سي ." المصرح به
We then go on to
ومن ثم نذهب
the first thing that was very surprising.
الى الشيء الاول المدهش جدا
If we put aluminum windows in this house,
وهو ان وضعنا نوافذ من الالومينوم في هذا المنزل
we would double the energy use right there.
فنحن نضاعف قيمة الطاقة المستخدمة هنا
Now, PVC is a little bit better,
وان استخدمنا نوافذ " البي في سي " نحصل على نتائج افضل
but still not as good as the wood that we chose.
ولكن ليس افضل من استخدم الخشب الذي اخترناه
We then put in plumbing,
ومن ثم نضع انابيب السباكة
electrical and HVAC,
والكهرباء والتكيف
and insulate.
والعزل
Now, spray foam is an excellent insulator -- it fills in all the cracks --
و رش مادة رغوية هو امر جيد جدا في العزل ,, لملأ الفراغات
but it is pretty high embodied energy,
ولكنا تحتاج طاقة مجسدة كبيرة
and, sprayed-in cellulose or blue jeans
ورش مادة سيلوزية او مادة " بلو جينز "
is a much lower energy alternative to that.
هو بديل يهدر طاقة اقل
We also used straw bale
ومن ثم نسخدم حزم القش
infill for our library,
لكي نملأ الجدران
which has zero embodied energy.
والتي لا تملك اي طاقة مجسدة على الاطلاق
When it comes time to sheetrock,
وعندما يأتي الامر إلى الالواح الصخرية
if you use EcoRock it's about a quarter
فإن استخدمت " أيكو روك " فإن ذلك سيكلفك ربع
of the embodied energy of standard sheetrock.
مقدار الطاقة التي تكلفك الالواح الصخرية العادية
And then you get to the finishes,
ومن ثم نصل الى التشطيبات
the subject of all of those "go green" articles,
والتي هي عنوان كل تلك المقالات البيئية
and on the scale of a house
على صعيد بناء المنازل
they almost make no difference at all.
في الواقع لا تؤثر على الاطلاق
And yet, all the press is focused on that.
ولكن الاعلام يركز عليها على الدوام
Except for flooring.
طبعاً بإستثناء أعمال الارضيات
If you put carpeting in your house,
فإن وضعت سجاد في المنزل
it's about a tenth of the embodied energy of the entire house,
فإنه يمثل عشرة بالمائة من طاقة المنزل المجسدة
unless you use concrete or wood
ولكن البيتون او الخشب
for a much lower embodied energy.
خيار بديل لطاقة مجسدة اقل
So now we add in the final construction energy, we add it all up,
ومن ثم نقوم بالاضافات النهائية للمنزل والتي تستهلك الطاقة
and we've built a house for less than half
وفي النهاية نكون قد بنينا منزل يستهلك نصف الطاقة
of the typical embodied energy for building a house like this.
- الطاقة المجسدة - الذي يستهلكها منزل إعتيادي
But before we pat ourselves
ولكن قبل أن نربت بانفسنا
too much on the back,
على ظهورنا فخرا بما قمنا به
we have poured 151 megawatt hours
علينا ان ننتبه الى اننا اضفنا 151 ميجا وات ساعي
of energy into constructing this house
لانشاء هذا المنزل
when there was a house there before.
على انقاض المنزل الذي كان موجود هنا سابقاً
And so the question is:
والسؤال هنا
How could we make that back?
كيف يمكننا استرداد هذه الطاقة ؟
And so if I run my new energy-efficient house forward,
الان ان قمنا بالنظر مستقبلنا الى المنزل الذي قمنا ببناءه
compared with the old, non-energy-efficient house,
مقارنة مع المنزل القديم والذي لايملك استهلاك امثل للطاقة
we make it back in about six years.
فاننا سوف نسترد هذه الطاقة المستهلكة خلال ستة سنوات
Now, I probably would have upgraded the old house
ولكن ماذا لو طورت المنزل القديم الى منزل
to be more energy-efficient,
يستهلك طاقة استهلاك امثل
and in that case,
في هذه الحالة
it would take me more about 20 years to break even.
سوف يتطلب الامر مني 20 عاما لكي اعادل الطاقة المهدورة
Now, if I hadn't paid attention to embodied energy,
ولكن ماذا لو أهملنا الطاقة المجسدة في بناء المنزل الجديد ..
it would have taken us
فإن هذا سوف يستهلك
over 50 years to break even
منا 50 عاما لكي نعادل
compared to the upgraded house.
المنزل المطور ذاك
So what does this mean?
إذا ماذا يعني هذا ؟
On the scale of my portion of the house,
على صعيد حصتي من طاقة المنزل ..
this is equivalent to about
فإنها تعادل ما يقارب
as much as I drive in a year,
الطاقة التي اصرفها عندما اقود سيارتي لمدة عام كامل
it's about five times as much
وهي تعادل خمس مرات الطاقة التي اكسبها
as if I went entirely vegetarian.
ان اصبحت نباتية تماما
But my elephant in the living room flies.
ولكن المشكلة الكبيرة تكون قد حلت
Clearly, I need to walk home from TED.
على العموم يبدو اني ساحتاج للعودة الى المنزل سيرا على الاقدام بعد مؤتمر تيد
But all the calculations
أنوه ان كل الحسابات
for embodied energy are on the blog.
عن الطاقة المجسدة موجودة على المدونة
And, remember, it's sometimes the things that you are not expecting
وتذكروا انها الاشياء التي لا نتوقعها على الاطلاق
to be the biggest changes that are.
هي التي تقوم بالتغيرات الاكبر
Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا ( تصفيق)